Ok,
let's get started...first of all I we had a lot of people come to the
booth asking if we're going to give away kits at the end of this session and
unfortunately we ran...so if you here for the kids I'm sorry we're not going to have any.
Well, and,
the good news though is that no one left so maybe we have an interesting talk here
...going to be a really practical
discussion about building real-live devices you know,
we had some great sessions already about building all join I'm going to talk
...a little bit about building all join devices with windows ten I ot
the touch a little bit about security and how to build real devices that you can using your
enterprise and talk a little bit about some of the experiences that
startups run into when...we may build...devices?
Has always...submit evaluations so that we can make this talk better each time?
One of the interesting to statistics
...gartner predicts is that by twenty seventeen half of the
rt solutions will be built by companies that are less than three-years-old
when I think about the...in computing
even in human history of it feels like we're in the middle of
one of them now if you think about fifty thousand years ago
was this proliferation of human tool use really latin group
out outpace the otherswhen I think about turbo
see turbo pascal and visual basic
the fundamentally change the number of developers that were in the ecosystem, you know,
previously there was about a hundred-thousand developers when these tools came out and
that and balloon to millions of developers very quickly
in a very short period of time and the great thing about that?
Evolution was that people were able to make money really quickly like there
was a cottage industry around building controls for vb there is a
cottage industry around building applications for people in
their business by people who were developers
who weren't trained as a traditional computer scientists
it really made available a
set of capabilities to customers to ordinary people that
...previously available and the same thing is true
rightnow the ability to take simple off-the-shelf hardware
to create prototypes take those prototypes in...you know,
for your own personal use but also to involve them into
products that you can use in your company products that you can sell to
other people products that you can sell to maker's
really enables people to explore business opportunities and enable
new scenarios that one available because you had to be an electrical engineer
to build these kinds of products so if you look at the modularity of
the shields of...availability of sensors
and the simplicity of the programming model that are doing now raspberry raspy
and foundation and microsoft complementing them really let-you evolve your
solution from a prototype into something that you can use in a business environment.
One of the most important pieces of our technology.
Is windows ten io t?
We provide for ua it's a platform.
A single device platform and a single app platform what that means is that the
Excuse me I'm getting over a little bit of a cold the...that-you that you and,
ecosystem build from one of these devices can be used as universal
...for the other
devices and ecosystem the applications that you right on
top of those universal on top of the universal windows platforms
the universal apps can be used across device if written correctly.
So, we've had a lot of focus on...in...show on
when this ten coyote core and it's really exciting, you know,
we have these
words that I'll show you a little bit later in the talk.
That...there were a little more difficult to program a little more difficult
to secure but now we have not only windows ten...core
windows...from mobile devices and I'll talk a little bit more about...same universal
applications but you can take these off-the-shelf...a...these
...five-dollar phones and use them...t solution they've got built-in t
pm they've got wi-fi they've got cellular you've got everything you need to make
a really amazing inexpensive io to device but we, you know,
sometimes get hung up on the need to see a real bored but if you want to build something
quickly we're seeing lots of folks use these is the platform that they'll build for.
And, then we have traditional windows ten io
t for industry devices and you can think about ...a pc's, you know,
like laptop sold laptop choosing those isiah to devices but companies like quantum
...tech have also built custom form factor
...for these very solutions.
So, that you can take out windows ten of windows ten device used
in the your enterprise with the same level of security and,
connectivity and our that you have on traditional desktops
it's really important to think about picking the right one
for the solution that you're building so if you look atwhen this ten io
t we tend to think about them into in terms of these sort of nested
dol diagramming though it's not entirely an accurate
van diagram it expresses the idea?
Of windows...ten for industry devices and if you need a
desktop experience if you need to shell if you me if you have existing when thirty-two
applications dot net micro framework wpf applications
...already deployed you can absolutely use windows ten...
For industry devices.
Now one of the interesting things that we've seen one folks use
of these windows ten devices on mobile is the need to
lock-down.
The need for...customize shell experiences
again when it's ten from mobile devices gives you all of the first party
...applications that you've already built that you can run
in highly customized environment
...off-the-shelf sort of consumer device for very
...very available device the last one,
you know, there I'll show several demos of today is
...ten for small devices windows ten...
...ten I ot core andwe'll talk a little bit more about this
doesn't come with the shout we've had lots of people actually ask what can I just use my
windows shell on here and this is really designed as a platform for you to take
your own application your own experience and use it...the primary
...is a collection of api that allow you to control that experience
and let-you load applications as the primary shelf for the product.
One of the important things for us to be successful.
Imis in...space is a
broad silicon support so you'll see us...ing in the booth and
...over the upcoming months demoing with more and more as silicon
support so intel we have...lots folks haven't seen them...max in
our booth if you go to the all join booth you'll see a lot of the demo on the middle
board max which I have here raspberry...of course so you'll
see us increasing our driver support increasing our board support.
So, right now I'm going to switch over to my demo machine
if I can get all of the switching right.
Great.
what I've what my coworkers and I've done is set up a few different machines here
...first show you
what taking a normal sort of windows phone application?
downloaded and I'm going to run in the emulator so I'm just going to take this.
And, run it so it's going to start up the emulator.
And, run the application.
And, this pretty simple applications actually just talking to a web service.
Grabbing the temperature and displaying it here using universal windows
application api so it's pretty, pretty simple pretty easy now what I'm going to do is
stop adaptation
switch over to the raspberry...
If you look here.
I'm actually not going to change any of the application.
And, I'm just going to build it.
What we've done beforehand islittle bit of setup where, you know,
we've put this on local network connected to it
...tcpip?
And, it's loading right now I'm just going to switch over to that.
So, here's the board.
And, visual studios busy loading.
...see the same application talking
to a service getting the same data without modification
just switch the target so what this means is that you really have a
lot of code re-use you can take a lot of the existing libraries that you have.
And, use those with very little if any modification on
these other windows...devices.
So, now let's take a look at you know, what all this means?
What we've done with the windows tan ire...
...core addition is added a and imbedded mode
embedded mode gives you the ability to access some of the important
api is that you need when you're building imbedded device or better application
this is policy manage because normally
you wpf applications operate in a sandbox.
They don't have access to all of hardware they don't have access to settings but
...mode either through certificate you put on
...machine or through policy.
You can actually turn this mode on these windows...devices so
that you can operate headlights so that you can.
Change settings so, for example.
Since you don't have a shel on this device you actually
have to use api to...bluetooth you have to use api to
connect to wireless networks you change the time.
Through api is because the shel we're so accustomed to having shell to do this
...add a number of api especially for applications that are running in the
...to be able
make these changes of course one most important ones is the ability
to access many buses that are available on these devices and
gp io I squared csp I and gps io which
really gives you the ability to interface with the real-world from universal application.
One of the other important pieces is the ability
to have a primary application have your application be specified as a
primary application so that once you've installed and on the device...the device free boots
...application is automatically
loaded but you also have the ability to.
You also have the ability to run this device as run applications in the
background
or specify a background application that you can use to service
...your foreground application your primary experience.
So, now let's switch over.
And, looked at
...application controlling hardware so you remember that application that I
...had before what I'm going to do now is I've modified it.
Instead of reading from.
The service.
...instead of reading from the service
we're going to do now is use the.
And, the gps...pans.
To read from this little sensor so this very tiny
...from our team built this really quickly and what it does is
itreads temperature and humidity right on the device?
What I'm down in switch over to the to another version
of this application where I've actually modified?
We've actually modify the application to read from.
The gps io pins.
Instead of readingfrom the service.
And, then I'm going to add deploy it.
One of the exciting things about being able to use visual studio for these
environment's is the ability to do real-time bugging on the device you have your
full tool set and.
That you can build your applications very quickly and easily.
Needed have a little song and dance...this thing gets deployed.
So, now I don't know if you can see it now where
it's theme application we've changed and now
treating the ambient temperature from the sensor and step...the service.
One of the important parts of working in.
...is collaborating, collaborating
with opensource the lots of open-source communities if you think.
If you think about communities that are out there there's a large
...large amount of source code that folks have
already built in python in node that
...used in a lot of these applications
...and that means there's a ton of innovation going on in the community as well so it was
really important for us to not only participate in the community inside this is
...sensitive
a and comes stealing thunder from the next part of the demo.
But, also to be good members of eq community and participate you know,
income to at humbly so, what you'll cs doing is working
with the python community the node community and, other groups that are really
working to build content and libraries for
io team so what we'll do is will continue to work with them will can...
make contributions back to those to those communities and will
...based on the communities that are most engage most interested in building
...solutions?
Now let's take a quick look at using node js
Actually build.
A management
applications what I've done so far as I've taken this device I took
the phone app moved on here rebuilt it we change
...code to read directly from sensor now what I'm going to do is
actually a create control panel a and experience for it
...that's completely written in node.
So, same thing here what we've done is.
Created...this no js application.
just taken...simple app and created same experience
so that you can access it from the web so how did same thing now deployed this no,
js application to the very same device and what you'll see is
...will probably be one layer but then what I'm going to do is a flip over
to the browser and open it up and the idea here is that,
you know, it's very easy to prototype on these platforms but as
you move forward it's important to be able to move quickly use existing
...components so that you don't have to build everything from scratch specially in sort
of startup?
Switch over here so we have is you'll see.
We have the ip address for this device.
And, I'll just reload.
And, you see.
That it to each time I refreshing you'll see that I'm
getting he live data from the sensor here can use the same
...node skills...already had
to build a device experience you may need a lot of hardware experience
...lot-of custom programming using the same tools that I'm
a custom to on the windows platform I can absolutely...management experience.
One of the most important things.
That we've been talking about the show.
Is the ability to connect the
windows ten devices windows ten solutions to other devices
because advice sitting by itself isn't really that interesting we have a collection of
...api...connect to physical hardwarethat's connected to
the ranks but there's alsoI'll join and what
we seem is up...join is...capability
for us to connect to other internet of things devices you'll see
...every single windows ten I ot when every single
when this ten addition and the great thing about all join is that it unify
...discovery security management of these devices
as well as being a open-source and cross-platform so, you know, if
you're building devices using other technology...the platforms all join works
...well so it makes it a great interopbetween windows ten
and these other devices?
All join has a ton of momentum right now is over hundred-fifty members and
it's still-growing the...alliance has a many industry leaders
...announcing new products every day.
So, then the interesting thing is what is that
topology and look like what is the network of these devices actually look like.
We have...when this in this diagram we have these windows
ten devices ...ten devices in the all
drawing network that natively speak all join but we also have
Refrigerators dot net boards...
A whole collection of existing devices that speak all
join we have a new technology that we announced at the
show that is a set of bridging technologies
to connect to connect windows tend to via the all join
as system butts so you'll see a very easy interface
for you to connect two-zero wave devices and back net so
from folks that aren't familiar with...most of us working
...buildings if you look at the if you look at the thermostat
that's on your in your officer down the hall those...usually connected via
...so this actually gives you the ability to wrap up
...field devices
or existing devices with all join using this kind of technology.
You have...
The ability to connect to these again these native all join devices
out an existing devices with all join
...so you can use a single api a single...
connectivity language to talk to all of these devices and then on top of this
you have asher so if you think about having these devices on
approximate network on a local subnet.
One of the challenges is that when you device leaves that's that subnet
you can't really get to those devices to manage them you can get to them to turn them on
our offer get state but with...here you can
...your device to connect to your services measure and use your add
...service as the
...these networks it really gives you a great deal of our without having to
know the intricacies of open
see wave without knowing the intricacies of back net you write to this
higher-level abstraction and get a great deal of connectivity let microsoft and
the gaussian alliance really worry about connecting to these very sources.
So, if you think about specifically what this looks like it's actually pretty easy so
what we have here instead of all of that sort of very
specific protocol code for z waivers igni you actually have
this call here for a new all join best
...that...connect you to the all join baths.
And, then I'm going to doing new temperature sensor on that paths and look,
for...discover temperature sensors that are on the bus and then finally
I'll do a reading from that...wait for
...sensor and get a reading from it so it's a much.
Simpler
way to discover these devices to connect to them and to get data from them and to...
So, now let's take a quick look to see how what.
Creating one of these systems looks like.
So, one of the important pieces of technology that we built in.
In windows ten is and all join
...device system bridge which is a universal windows application
it's actually component that you use in your windows universal application.
We give you all the code...we have it available
...so I'm going to do here.
Is I'm going to create this new project?
And, what you'll see?
Generating atomic hope.
Look, at the project.
You can see there's quite a bit of code here.
If you want to you can actually get in here and modify yourself.
But, for the most part you can ignore the code that's in that's in
there what I'm going to now is actually.
...a reference.
So, that I can use the app windows ten ip extensions.
And, I'm actually building an application that will deploy to the smm.
What I have to do is well is?
...just change the adaptor code.
Actually...
And, then I can change the.
Header.
What I'm doing here and this code is actually changing the
base generated application so that instead of instead of
...all implementation of actually reading from the sensors that are here as
well as connecting to a couple of all join devices?
So, now I'm going...
Deploy.
This is actually going to take a little while.
So, I'll just switch...rare.
While this deploys.
And, I'll talk a little bit about what?
We had the...that we have here so...a min aboard max which is an x eighty-six
basedcomputer we have a little light sensor here.
We also havethe windows speech api that we're using with
this as well so it has the ability to
do continuous speech recognition is where as well as text-to-speech.
Now we have.
Z wave radio and we have this
the switch connected to a really cool shade that is
all lecture dramatic shade.
When you apply current too it changes state from opaque to clear we have a
light?
So, I think we're just about done deploying.
...a microphone.
Because it was networking earlier now it's like so I'm.
Tried...but it didn't work we haven't working in the booty should come take a look at you know,
we...put this together really quickly at the last-minute but the idea here is there are many
components.
But, you have that you can pull together so that you don't have to build these products
from scratch imagine if you go have to go out and integrate a speech api from
somewhere else.
A...trying to make it look bad now.
If you had to try...speech api if you had to license all the z
wave components to try and get this to work be really difficult expensive
...ton of legal issues involved and it's keeping you from actually getting to
the point of building the solution that you want to build quickly using the skills that you already have.
So, what you'll see
...you'll see I'm going to put the microphone away
what you'll see is a continual pattern of a large number
of reusable components andavailability of the tools that you already u?
As you start to think about deploying projects based on this
technology's technologies one big challenges
is security I don't know if you read about one of the
most interesting security exploits recently there was a company that purchase.
There...a company...purchased a.
...a company the purchased some off-the-shelf computing devices as some of them were
tablet some of them where.
For computers and what they did was install
...where on these computers and on these tablets...may sold them on ebay?
People started using them.
And, now one of them was in fact hub they had purchased home hub what they
data on hub was put a map on hub
...actually sent all the traffic back to the hackers
server they were able to see all of the traffic that went over this
person's home network they were able to get credit card numbers,
you know,
passwords everything so when you think about securing these devices
you know, right nowso, many folks are excited about just getting them working,
you know, we really have to start thinking about how to secure them.
So, one of the one of the features that you'll see...out windows
...hand-eye...I think is important and differentiating is
to pm...pm is actually a device that you
can put on your computer on your socp that.
Allows you to securely store secrets we support a variety of different
...pm types we have on-chip so if in fact you look at
phones many phones and some of your computers of on-chip
...we've got firmware
...pm so that you can do development you know,
on your on one of these boards
...to pm and even deploy to...without t p.
We have announce and I think you'll see as...blog posts around
...that you can connect on windows ten io t over I squared...
so working with several partners in the community to make these available as well as a
...pm simulator and what this allows you to do is have things like
now where protection for secure...so when
...able to profile the boop performance of your device we can
...if something's been injected into that device and,
isolated so that it's not a vector format where?
When we think about connecting these devices to?
To networks typically there's no you
...so when you think about connecting to why fire networking
need to certificate you could store that certificate or password in
the clear on the on st card
imis device but then I'll someone needs to do is pop out the...card
read it and then they can they have your credentials they have used to
forget in fact they have your network with...pm you can actually store those secrets
...a safe place and, guarantee their security?
...resistance tampering via...gives you
...level of our authenticity and authentication the couldn't get with
...that doesn't have these features so if you think about building
your own solution surely easy to create that prototype but
when you go from creating that prototype to deploying it in an
enterprise environment's really important...think about all of these features as well as you know,
things like divisive encryption so that you can actually secure the...as well.
As I said earlier when
...devices...to devices in general come in many shapes
had an earlier version of this slide with I don't know if you've seen them the one of the giant
cockroaches with...chip on top at the slide folks thought it was inappropriate so this
is been sanitized for your viewing but, you know,...different kinds of
...devices and I said earlierwindows...make a great coyote device
...you think about customizing your experience if you take in windows ten file.
And, you put your application is the primary application using our
lock-down features you could have your application always...if you have multiple
users so if you look atseveral of the largeretail houses, you know,
they will have many employee sharingsharing advice and also have
different types of employee sharing devices so we have the ability lock-down the
experience on windows phone and all the windows ten io to devices such that you can
say this
specific user has the ability to run these applications are access these parts of the
...or notional it all we have the ability to say this
roller this kind of user has access to this type of
functionality so this is what you're seeing here in this slide you can see we have the
ability switch...manager and...
They login as soon as they login depending on their login we know which role they
are a set of applications that they can get to based on our lock-down features.
In building io to devices
...lots of times where you want to plugging...tool wall and forget
about it you don't want updates coming out every tuesday from microsoft and,
in that case we need to give you the ability to control when
updates happen and which type of updates and you might decide that you don't want
any updates at all so with windows coyote we give the ability to always
...lots of people who are going to want to see updates on a devices all the time so
they can ensure that...secure an up-to-date?
With some folks that just for their application only want to get security updates because they don't want
to new features they want to relatively
...the devices and select important updates and then the final one
as I mentioned before is hey, I'm...going to plug the san and...
one-c and update because I only want to update the device...update my application
the full stack on the device so this is a new feature
...set of features that we've ...windows ten.
...take the analogy further so I've built this divisive secured it I
Make sure that I've set the updates correctly for
this situation I'm in and then the final part is how do I manage these,
you know, in the early days of
pc's we have lots of people just sort of connect connecting devices on
at connecting computers onto the corporate network and there wasn't this
notion of management early on but it really became important very quickly we're seeing the same
type of thing happen now with when with...devices the ability to
...these devices to...gather
...state to deploy them to deploying new firmware to them is
...important part of being able to
...devices into the enterprise so what you'll see for windows ten-hour to devices is
built in the ability to manage these devices with existing
Software
either third-party or system center from microsoft.
Mem includes the devices based on industry
mobile or when it's ten core?
So, now we have this...
Set of features for recruit prototyping my device ...you know,
locking down the experience securing it and managing
...last part is really like how do I develop it how do I build it.
What we have is the ability to create a what we call a full flash image
...you'll hear lots of us talk about...use and
...use are just a real it's really simply a disk image the disk image that,
you know, for example,...the device on if you look at these two guys
they're actually the disk image that's on the...card and it makes it really easy for you
to pick the application pick the drivers?
Pick the settings that you want and put in a single image and take that image and
replicated, you know, as many times you want.
We have a tool you can use do this from the command-line we also have a tool called the
windows...image configuration designer
and we usually call it icd and this application
...sort of visually control what?
Settings there are apps and configuration.
So, you take the operating system package.
And, you have feature manifest.
You take the board support packed in the board support package can actually be
...drivers.
You might have
...and several other components that you need to bring up this device
...you combine all of these together along with
a customization in settings andinto one package use
the windowsimaging image configuration designer image app to create this
Now the...
Is then used with fu tool to directly
flash multiple images which can also make a golden master?
...take that golden master and replicated in fact for
the robot kits that we gave all of view we did exactly that we
made golden master one of the guys on our team actually drove
to oregon four hours from redmond handed the
...card to the replicated may produced about four hundred
fifty st cards for us that we then put in each of the robots that we
gave way yesterday you can also do this manually as I mention here with
icd or tool that that's called this and if you go to
windows on devices dot com we actually walk you through the process of creating
...image putting it on the...card and then putting...your device.
So, we've created this very easy experience for you to create your
image to customize it so that you can create a custom device.
So,... I think a lot of you may be asking what you do next.
I think there's a ton of creativity, you know,
in the community when we've seen people come to the booth there's lots
of existing applications that folks have built we were talking with one
german yesterday and booth that has a little application that he'd used from a
phone.
That used open see...cv open computer vision to
do face detection and what he wanted to do is take one of these
devices one of these raspberry pies or...put a
camera on it and make a little panel that you have on your front door
to face detection and...amounts people when they come to your door and
like he doesn't need any electrical engineering skills he's actually
been at a while...had to show emailing me
asking me questions about how to use this and the idea of, you know,
this cool acted he's built with off-the-shelf components taking it from
...some ideas some sample code
...actually put in the windows store to creating a device working with
...am and oem to make these
and quantity is really exciting, you know,
it's a it's an ability for folks to build appliances that, you know,
we really couldn't build before very easily unless we had a great deal of backing or
ton of expertise so I'm
...you to do the same thing take your ideas take the core projects that you
have think about how to make them appliances or other solutions that
you can sell up to either...people in the community or to
consumers and, you know, use...ten ire...and one of
our additions try your...on raspberry
pi and then join...on now windows on devices dot com?
Thank you.
So, they asked me to be to finish about fifteen minutes early we ran along
if you're interested will stick around for questions please feel free to,
come on, up have a few folks from the team so one of the should be able to help you out thanks-again?